Rian Arthur Rutherford



Email - rianrutherford@outlook.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio Website

About Me

Programmer | England, UK

Hobbyist, educational, and professional years combined I have 7 years of programming experience. Since 2022 I have been working towards becoming a multiplayer and networking specialist for game development. Recent projects have been replicated player movement for Arcade from scratch, and server authoritative lock on systems like in Armour Core 6.

Currently I am learning basic serverside sys admin - docker & simple server hardening.

Education

BA(Hons) Game Development: Programming Falmouth University, England; 2021 - 2024

Level 3 Computing BTEC Extended Diploma Weston College, England; 2019 - 2021

Work Experience

West Forge: Jun 2024 - Present Freelance programmer developing Stormbane.

My roles on the project are Gameplay Programmer and Multiplayer Systems Engineer.

Blockception: Nov 2017 - Nov 2022

Freelance programmer developing Minecraft Maps for the Minecraft Marketplace.

Work on: The Moa'ul Mountain, Dragon's Tale, and Mountain Retreat.

Interests

I like playing Dungeons & Dragons, watching anime, and occasionally playing games. RTS and MMO are my favourite game genres.

Games I've enjoyed playing recently are Helldivers, Homeworld: Deserts of Kharak, Armoured Core 6, and Higan: Eruthyll.

I have an interest in how game engines work, and sometimes think it would be fun till I realise how much work it would be to develop the tooling.

Skills

Programming Languages

C++ | Rust | Blueprints | Python | GDScript | C#

Game Engines

Unreal Engine 5 | Godot | Unity | Bevy

Projects

Arcade: Sept 2023 - Present

3D, PVP, multiplayer, drone spaceship, area fighting game where players fight each other using homing missiles.

Lock On System: Nov 2024

Prototype lock on system in UE5 using virtual screens enabling for server authoritative targeting/lock on and entity direction relative lock on

1k Muliplayer Research Essay: 2024

My 3rd year university research essay exploring how to develop 1k+ game servers from the technical side.

Swamp Fell: Sept 2023 - May 2024
3D game with action combat and questing, made in Unreal Engine 5. Team of eight.
Worked on modular health component, enemy AI, and quest system.

Wrong Turn at... Convention: Dec 2023 2D roguelike made using Bevy and Rust for a

2D roguelike made using <u>Bevy</u> and <u>Rust</u> for a game jam. I made the AI and camera controller. Video by member of team <u>here</u>.